Keith Marshall Collection of Photographs
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Oversize, Series III
  - Maori portraits and Mariannhill Monastery
    - Portrait of Wiremu and Rangitoia / Portrait of Tāwhiao, Maori King, 1880s; Pulman and Son Photographers; 2 albumen prints mounted on either side of a black paper sheet; 27.5 x 21 cm (both images) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      The photo on the front depicts two Maori women, with names tattooed on their arms. One woman has the name "Wiremu" on her arm, and the other has "Rangitoia." The women touch foreheads, a traditional greeting.
      On the reverse side is a portrait of Tawhiao, Maori King. He wears a heavy woven cloak and has elaborate facial tattoos.
      Both images are signed by Pulman photo.
      Albumen prints; Maori (New Zealand people) -- Portraits; Portraits; Tāwhiao, King of the Māori, fl. 1860-1894
    - Cango Caves Interior, Prince Albert, Oudtshoorn Road, circa 1900; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851-1950; 1 photograph in a cardboard mat; 28.5 x 22.5 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      With the ink stamp of T.D. Ravenscroft on the reverse.
      Photographs; South Africa; Cango Caves (South Africa)
    - Monks at Mariannhill Monastery (2 photographs), circa 1900; 2 photographs, mounted on single paper sheet; 13.5 x 21 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      Two images of monks at the Mariannhill Monastery. The first shows monks at work making wine, perhaps. The second is labeled: "Refectorium, Mariannhill." The monks are at a meal, and eating silently while a reading is made by the monk sitting in a small elevated pulpit at right.
      Photographs; Mariannhill Missionaries; Mariannhill (Monastery)
    - Monks at a stream, likely near Mariannhill Monastery, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 13 x 20.5 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      The monks are resting at a stream. With them are a few African boys who wear Western-style outfits of shirts, trousers, and suspenders, with straw hats.
    - Two photographs of classes, likely at (or near) Mariannhill Monastery, 1880s or 1890s; 2 photographs; 13.5 x 21 cm (each) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      Two images of education of South African children, likely at Mariannhill Monastery. The first image shows a nun teaching four girls how to sew. This may be a studio shot. The second photo depicts a class conducted outdoors.
      Missions -- South Africa; Photographs; Mariannhill Missionaries; Mariannhill (Monastery)
    - A wedding procession, likely at Mariannhill Monastery, 1880s or 1890s; 1 photograph; 13.5 x 21 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      Files of men and women walk behind the bridal couple, and a monk looks on at right. Likely one of a series of photos taken at Mariannhill Monastery.
      Photographs; Missions -- South Africa; Mariannhill Missionaries; Mariannhill (Monastery)
  - China and Funchal
    - Two small sailboats, circa 1900; 1 albumen print; 15.5 x 20.5 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 3)
      The sails appear to be of Eastern design, perhaps Chinese.
    - Seven photographs of scenes in China, after 1850; 7 albumen prints, mounted on a large black paper sheet (both sides); 11.5 x 16.5 cm (each) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 3)
      Seven images of Chinese architecture, citizens, landscapes. The images may be associated with the Mariannhill Missionaries.
      Albumen prints; China; Mariannhill Missionaries
    - Photograph of a settlement in Asia, possibly China, circa 1900; 1 albumen print, mounted on large paper sheet; 11.5 x 17 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 3)
      The image may be associated with the Mariannhill Missionaries.
    - Four images of scenes in China / Two images of unidentified street scenes, possibly in Funchal, circa 1900; 4 albumen prints, 2 photographs; 16.5 x 12 cm and 12 x 16.5 cm (albumen prints) and 23.5 x 17.5 cm and 17.5 x 23.5 cm (photographs) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 3)
      The four albumen prints of scenes in China depict art, architecture, and local people. The images may be associated with the Mariannhill Missionaries.
      Albumen prints; China; Funchal (Madeira Islands); Photographs; Mariannhill Missionaries
    - Four images of scenes in China / Two images of Funchal (?), circa 1900; 4 albumen prints, 2 photographs, mounted on both sides of a paper sheet; 11.5 x 17cm(albumen) 17.5 x 23.5 cm (photographs) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 3)
      Four images of various scenes in China, some of architecture, one rooftop view of a village, and one scene of a woman in Western dress holding an infant at some sort of stone building. Two images of Madeira, one labeled "Camara de Lobos." Possibly related to Mariannhill Mission/Monastery, represented in other images belonging to the same set of former album pages.
      Photographs; Funchal (Madeira Islands); China; Albumen prints; Mariannhill Missionaries
    - Coastal area / Unidentified town, circa 1900; 2 photographs, mounted on a large paper sheet; 16 x 21 cm (each) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 3)